this place
여기
I stayed longer than you
내가 너보다 오래 머물렀어
I've only seen people coming in
사람들이 들어오는 걸 본 적이 있어요
I've never seen anyone go out before
난 지금까지 밖에 나가는 사람을 본 적이 없어
Stop wishful thinking
희망적인 생각을 멈추세요
Run away with me
나와 함께 도망
You still have a chance
아직 기회가 있어요
I'll think about it
나는 그것에 대해 생각합니다
nothing to consider
고려할 것이 없다
If you stay here, you can only wait for death.
여기에 머무르면 죽음만 기다릴 수 있다.
What you said makes sense.
당신이 말한 것은 의미가 있습니다.
Then I'll run out with you
그럼 난 너와 함께 달려갈게
What good do I have?
나한테 무슨 소용이 있어?
what benefits do you want
어떤 혜택을 원하시나요?
Give me money
돈을 줘
I save your life
나는 당신의 생명을 구합니다
I also want to give you money
나도 돈 주고싶다
Of course you have to give me money
당연히 돈을 줘야지
I didn't need to run for the first time
처음에는 달릴 필요가 없었어요
I know your secret now
난 이제 너의 비밀을 알아
I have to run with you
너와 함께 달려야 해
second
두번째
You forgot the most important thing
가장 중요한 것을 잊으셨나요?
Those keys of yours
당신의 그 열쇠
not enough
부족한
And the last key?
그리고 마지막 열쇠는요?
you don't have that key
너 그 열쇠 없어
No matter how many doors you open
아무리 많은 문을 열어도
You can't escape either
너도 도망칠 수 없어
that key
그 열쇠
Nishimura is not hanging on his waist
니시무라는 허리에 매달려 있지 않습니다
He usually keeps it with his private key.
그는 보통 자신의 개인 키로 이를 보관합니다.
It's in his left trouser pocket
왼쪽 바지 주머니에 있어요
Are you sure you have the ability to get the key?
열쇠를 얻을 수 있는 능력이 확실합니까?
really uncertain
정말 불확실하다
Please tell me first how much money you can give me.
나에게 얼마를 줄 수 있는지 먼저 말해주세요.
How much do you want
얼마를 원하세요?
one thousand
천
I don't have that much money
나 돈이 그렇게 많지 않아
Aren't you wasting your time here?
여기서 시간을 낭비하고 있지는 않나요?
you have no money
당신은 돈이 없습니다
What are you doing out there?
밖에서 뭐하고 있어요?
Might as well stay here
여기 머무르는 게 나을지도 몰라
Eat together
같이 먹자
Eight hundred
팔? 백
All my property
내 모든 재산
How about it
어때요?
do you recognize that key
그 열쇠 알아?
The nose was cut off
코가 잘렸네
I don't have it, sir.
저는 그것을 갖고 있지 않습니다.
I'm not that cruel
나 그렇게 잔인하진 않아
He said he didn't
그는 그렇지 않다고 하더군요
He has it
그는 그것을 가지고 있다
Indeed there are
실제로 있습니다
He has a knife in his hand
그는 손에 칼을 들고 있다
Yeah
응
sir
선생님
There's something wrong with this guy's brain
이 사람 뇌에 뭔가 문제가 있는 것 같아
Do you think this is a knife?
이게 칼인 것 같나요?
This is what I usually use to trim my nails.
제가 손톱 깎을 때 주로 사용하는 방법이에요.
There's no problem with this
이건 문제없어요
Yes, sir
알겠습니다
You can't trust him
당신은 그를 믿을 수 없습니다
sir
선생님
You must make the decision for me, sir.
저를 대신해 결정을 내려주셔야 합니다.
you save me
당신이 나를 구해줬어요
Is this a knife?
이건 칼인가요?
Look
바라보다
The nose is still on the face
코가 아직 얼굴에 붙어있네
Are you kidding me?
농담하는 거야?
do you want to die
죽고 싶니?
Don't, don't
하지마, 하지마
I'll help you
내가 도와 줄게
sir
선생님
dream dream dream
꿈 꿈 꿈
that
저것
You're not talking about him
당신은 그 사람에 대해 말하는 것이 아닙니다
Always loves to dig people’s eyes out
항상 사람들의 눈을 파는 것을 좋아합니다.
Bite your ears?
귀를 물어요?
I just had a dream
방금 꿈을 꿨어요
too real
너무 현실적이다
Be honest
솔직해지세요
If you make trouble again, I'll kill you
또 문제 일으키면 죽여버릴 거야
sir
선생님
treat him well
그 사람을 잘 대해줘
Sorry to disturb your rest
휴식을 방해해서 죄송합니다
sorry
죄송합니다
Get along with
함께 지내다
I don’t dare anymore. I don’t dare anymore.
더 이상 감히 할 수 없습니다. 더 이상 감히 할 수 없습니다.
This key is divided into three parts
이 키는 세 부분으로 나누어져 있습니다.
length of key
키의 길이
Equivalent to the total length of your index finger
검지 전체 길이와 같습니다.
length of key body
키 본체의 길이
Equivalent to the first joint of the index finger
검지의 첫 번째 관절에 해당
and the length of the second joint
두 번째 관절의 길이
There is a third part
세 번째 부분이 있습니다
The sawtooth part is square
톱니부분이 사각형이다
Grooves on three sides
세 면에 홈이 있음
Equilateral length
등변 길이
One-third of your first knuckle
첫 번째 관절의 3분의 1
Don’t worry, I’ve remembered everything clearly.
걱정하지 마세요. 저는 모든 것을 선명하게 기억하고 있습니다.
Don't be too happy too early
너무 일찍 너무 기뻐하지 마세요
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
material for making keys
열쇠 제작 재료
have nothing left
아무것도 남지 않았다
no
아니요
There are so many hinges on this bed
이 침대에는 경첩이 너무 많아요
You've used it all
다 써보셨군요
Do you really think that the materials I made earlier
제가 아까 만든 자료가 정말 그럴 거라고 생각하시나요?
Is it a success every time?
매번 성공인가요?
Available now
지금 이용 가능
It’s not that the thickness is not enough
굵기가 부족한건 아닌데
Otherwise, it will be rusty
그렇지 않으면 녹슬게 됩니다.
What about wood?
나무는 어떻습니까?
Wood is too brittle
나무가 너무 부서지기 쉬우니까
I can't bear the exertion at all
나는 그 노력을 전혀 견딜 수 없다
This should work
이것은 작동합니다
Mahogany
마호가니
Definitely hard enough
확실히 충분히 힘들어
If you carve along the wood grain
나뭇결을 따라 조각하면
It shouldn't be a big problem
큰 문제는 아닐 텐데
Mr. Yamashita
Mr. Yamashita
Then I'll go home first
그럼 나 먼저 집에 갈게
Since we are getting married
우리 결혼하니까
Just don’t call me Mr. Yamashita.
그냥 야마시타 씨라고 부르지 마세요.
OK
좋아요
Tonight's press conference
오늘밤 기자회견
I am very satisfied
나는 매우 만족한다
Are you tired too?
당신도 피곤해요?
Go home early and rest
일찍 집에 가서 쉬어라
good
좋은
The copper plate of border coins is in Wang Dapu's hands
국경 동전의 동판은 Wang Dapu의 손에 있습니다
He was anxious to escape
그는 탈출을 열망했다
The copper plate must be handed over to the military commander
동판은 군 사령관에게 넘겨야합니다
Just follow him
그냥 그를 따라가세요
You can find the copper plate
구리판을 찾을 수 있습니다.
It surprised me that
그 점에 놀랐어요
Jiang Zhao would do such a thing
장자오가 그런 짓을 할 텐데
I think
제 생각에는
Maybe you don't know him
어쩌면 당신은 그 사람을 모를 수도 있습니다
Do not worry
걱정 하지마
I will convince him
나는 그를 설득할 것이다
correct
옳은
Did Yamashita tell you about the Sugi Project?
야마시타가 스기 프로젝트에 대해 말했나요?
No
아니요
But Fujita, the driver at Yamashita, told me
그런데 야마시타의 운전기사인 후지타가 나에게 말했다.
Yamashita is working for the Empire of Japan
야마시타는 일본제국을 위해 일하고 있다
do something great
뭔가 대단한 일을 해라
how about you
당신은 어떤가요
What are your plans for the future?
미래에 대한 당신의 계획은 무엇입니까?
I really want to marry Yamashita
나는 정말로 야마시타와 결혼하고 싶다
I've already planned it
난 이미 계획을 세웠어
Have you brought anything?
뭐 가져오셨나요?
Don't worry, it's colorless and odorless
걱정하지 마세요. 무색, 무취입니다.
Is it toxic enough?
충분히 독성이 있나요?
It's okay to poison a horse to death
말을 독살해도 괜찮습니다
Lieutenant Commander Uchida promised me
우치다 중령이 약속했어요
Can be alone with Mr. Jiang
장씨와 단둘이 있을 수 있다
This skirt is still there
이 스커트는 아직 남아있어요
Why do you want to frame Chen Jiaping?
왜 Chen Jiaping을 모함하고 싶습니까?
It turns out you came to me because of this matter.
이 문제 때문에 당신이 나에게 온 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.
Why
왜
this is politics
이것이 정치다
You do not understand
당신은 이해하지 않는다
I don’t understand politics
나는 정치를 이해하지 못한다
But I understand someone
하지만 나는 누군가를 이해한다
You should have the minimum integrity and conscience
최소한의 성실성과 양심을 가져야 합니다.
anyway
그래도
No one should be framed
누구도 액자에 넣어서는 안 된다
people who have helped you
당신을 도와준 사람들
Zuo Shuangtao asked you to come, right?
Zuo Shuangtao가 오라고 했죠?
Chen Jiaping was very helpful to me.
Chen Jiaping은 나에게 매우 도움이 되었습니다.
After you return to Chongqing
충칭으로 돌아온 후
I once couldn't think about it
한때는 그것에 대해 생각할 수 없었습니다
If it weren't for Chen Jiaping
천자핑이 아니었다면
I'm already dead
나는 이미 죽었어
why didn't you tell me earlier
왜 나한테 미리 말 안 했어?
Chen Jiaping was imprisoned in a detention center by the Japanese
천자핑은 일본군에 의해 구치소에 투옥되었습니다.
Only if you change your confession
고백만 바꾸면
Only then can we save him
그래야만 그를 구할 수 있다
good
좋은
I promise you
약속 할게
You need to tell Uchida
우치다에게 말해야 해
The person who gave you the labor certificate is Zhao An
당신에게 노동증명서를 준 사람은 자오안입니다.
Zhao An is the real Five of Hearts
자오안은 진짜 5심이다
Want to put the blame on Zhao An
조안(Zhao An)을 비난하고 싶다
Just relying on my confession
내 고백에만 의지해
I'm afraid it's not enough
부족할까봐
They have other plans
그 사람들은 다른 계획이 있어
All you have to do is say this
이 말만 하면 돼
Just think of it as the last thing you can do for me.
그것이 당신이 나를 위해 할 수 있는 마지막 일이라고 생각해주세요.
one last thing
마지막 한가지
What do you mean
무슨 뜻이에요
When are you going to see Uchida?
우치다를 언제 만나러 가시나요?
Noon
정오
Every day at noon
매일 정오
Uchida will return to the Military Police Headquarters
우치다는 헌병 본부에 복귀한다
Then I'll see you again in the afternoon
그럼 오후에 다시 만나요
come to me again
다시 내게로 와
I saw that Xinghualou’s mung bean cake is on the market again.
Xinghualou의 녹두 케이크가 다시 시장에 나오는 것을 봤습니다.
I want to buy some and come over to eat with you
좀 사서 너랑 같이 먹으러 가고 싶어
Uchida
우치다
Will you be allowed to come to me again and again?
당신은 나에게 몇 번이고 다시 올 수 있습니까?
This is also the military police headquarters anyway.
어차피 이곳은 헌병대 본부이기도 하다.
You can't escape either
너도 도망칠 수 없어
Isn't it?
그렇지 않나요?
yes
예
This is the military police headquarters
이곳은 헌병본부다.
Can't escape
탈출할 수 없어
do you remember
기억 나니
Have we taken a photo together before?
우리 예전에 같이 사진 찍은 적 있었나요?
You were also wearing this skirt that day
그 날 너도 이 치마를 입었지
the weather that day
그날 날씨
also very good
또한 아주 좋은
Miss Hanlu
미스 한루
What a coincidence
이런 우연이
you are here too
너도 여기 있어
correct
옳은
congratulations
축하해요
What do you congratulate me on?
무슨 일로 축하해?
What does this mean
이것은 무엇을 의미 하는가
Haven't you seen it all?
다 못 봤어?
Did you promise him?
그 사람에게 약속했어요?
When you spoke, did you answer him?
당신이 말했을 때 그에게 대답했습니까?
Yesterday they said they were going to execute you
어제 사람들이 당신을 처형하겠다고 하더군요
if i don't agree
내가 동의하지 않는다면
Who is Shanxia?
산샤는 누구인가?
All I know is that Uchida is helping him
내가 아는 건 우치다가 그를 돕고 있다는 것 뿐이다.
he has great power
그는 큰 힘을 가지고 있어요
Why didn't I think of it earlier?
Why didn't I think of it earlier?
Yamashita Takeo
Yamashita Takeo
He is the controller of Project Sugi
He is the controller of Project Sugi
he is the one
he is the one
what are you going to do
what are you going to do
You have already bought the mung bean cake
You have already bought the mung bean cake
What is this, what is this?
What is this, what is this?
you give me
you give me
Bring it over and show it to me
Bring it over and show it to me
What's this
What's this
Give me
Give me
Poison?
Poison?
Do you want to poison me to death?
Do you want to poison me to death?
You want to sprinkle it on mung bean cake
You want to sprinkle it on mung bean cake
Let me eat it and poison me to death, right?
Let me eat it and poison me to death, right?
yes
yes
I just want to poison you to death
I just want to poison you to death
But I don't just want to poison you
But I don't just want to poison you
I want to eat mung bean cake with you
I want to eat mung bean cake with you
I'll die with you
I'll die with you
you are crazy
you are crazy
I'm not crazy
I'm not crazy
I know very well what Yamashita Takeo's methods are.
I know very well what Yamashita Takeo's methods are.
He won't let you go
He won't let you go
He won't let me go either
He won't let me go either
He will use you as a weight to blackmail me.
He will use you as a weight to blackmail me.
the two of us
the two of us
The two of us forever
The two of us forever
Don't even think about getting rid of him
Don't even think about getting rid of him
you are really crazy
you are really crazy
I can't die, you know?
I can't die, you know?
I have a mission
I have a mission
I have to live well
I have to live well
I can't die with you
I can't die with you
Are you still alive like this?
Are you still alive like this?
You have to get me out
You have to get me out
I have to get out of here
I have to get out of here
Takeo Yamashita is the controller of Project Sugi
Takeo Yamashita is the controller of Project Sugi
he loves you so much
he loves you so much
You must have a way
You must have a way
Asked him to let me out
Asked him to let me out
did you mean
did you mean
Let me really marry Yamashita
Let me really marry Yamashita
to exchange for your freedom
to exchange for your freedom
If we are still together in the future
If we are still together in the future
you
you
Can you just make a little sacrifice?
Can you just make a little sacrifice?
did you mean
did you mean
I want to keep Yamashita’s dirty hands off
I want to keep Yamashita???s dirty hands off
touch me again
touch me again
Will you taint me again?
Will you taint me again?
Hanlu, listen to me
Hanlu, listen to me
I don't want to hear you anymore
I don't want to hear you anymore
every word you say
every word you say
They are all insulting me
They are all insulting me
They are all insulting our love
They are all insulting our love
I beg you
I beg you
help me again
help me again
How about the last time?
How about the last time?
Help you once
Help you once
Then who am I?
Then who am I?
After I go out
After I go out
I
I
After I destroyed the Shan Project
After I destroyed the Shan Project
you are like me
you are like me
All are heroes
All are heroes
hero
hero
Do you think I want to be a hero?
Do you think I want to be a hero?
Since you don't help me
Since you don't help me
I just insist
I just insist
Chen Jiaping is the Five of Hearts
Chen Jiaping is the Five of Hearts
You are really despicable
You are really despicable
Don’t you want to help Chen Jiaping?
Don???t you want to help Chen Jiaping?
Don't you want to save him?
Don't you want to save him?
OK
OK
no problem
no problem
Get me out first
Get me out first
I want to get Yamashita Takeo
I want to get Yamashita Takeo
After hand-signed release order
After hand-signed release order
I immediately changed my mind
I immediately changed my mind
do you know
do you know
Yamashita Takeo
Yamashita Takeo
He is very gentle to me on the surface
He is very gentle to me on the surface
But he is actually a complete pervert
But he is actually a complete pervert
We are all adults
We are all adults
I do not care
I do not care
You, you are shameless
You, you are shameless
How long until it arrives
How long until it arrives
It's going to be there in less than five minutes.
It's going to be there in less than five minutes.
parking
parking
Parking Parking
Parking Parking
What happened to Captain Zhao?
What happened to Captain Zhao?
fine
fine
I'll put some water in
I'll put some water in
Wait for me
Wait for me
Tom
Tom
I'm going to discuss something with Trunk
I'm going to discuss something with Trunk
You go first and drive quickly
You go first and drive quickly
Captain, it's almost too late
Captain, it's almost too late
It's almost time
It's almost time
That's too late
That's too late
Let me tell the car behind me something
Let me tell the car behind me something
Follow
Follow
It's almost too late
It's almost too late
Follow quickly
Follow quickly
Go, go, go
Go, go, go
What happened to the captain?
What happened to the captain?
keep up keep up keep up
keep up keep up keep up
Chief Uchida
Chief Uchida
cotton yarn
cotton yarn
Please convey my gratitude to Mr. Yamashita for me.
Please convey my gratitude to Mr. Yamashita for me.
Mr. Yamashita said
Mr. Yamashita said
This is his first time
This is his first time
Also the last time
Also the last time
Let go of your enemies with your own hands
Let go of your enemies with your own hands
Since Mr. Yamashita gives me such face,
Since Mr. Yamashita gives me such face,
Then I will also give Mr. Yamashita a gift.
Then I will also give Mr. Yamashita a gift.
what gift
what gift
a truth
a truth
you say
you say
In fact, Chen Jiaping
실제로 천자핑(Chen Jiaping)은
Not the five of hearts
하트 5개 아님
I deliberately put the blame on him
나는 일부러 그 사람에게 책임을 돌렸다.
why did you do this
왜이 짓을 했나요
because before i
왜냐하면 나보다 먼저
I heard that his relationship with Han Lu is very ambiguous.
한루와의 관계가 매우 모호하다고 들었습니다.
But what I didn't expect was
하지만 내가 기대하지 않았던 것은
She betrayed me
그녀는 나를 배신했다
It’s not Chen Jiaping
천자핑은 아니지???
But Yamashita Takeo
But Yamashita Takeo
So there is no need for me to frame Chen Jiaping
그러니 Chen Jiaping을 모함할 필요가 없습니다.
You said it before
전에도 말했잖아
Now suddenly changed his mind
이제 갑자기 마음이 바뀌었어요
Do you think I would believe it?
내가 믿을 것 같나요?
Do you believe it or not?
믿거나 말거나?
Is it important to me?
나에게 중요합니까?
It's the cold dew that asks for something from me
나에게 무엇인가를 요구하는 것은 차가운 이슬이다
I just told you the truth
난 방금 진실을 말했어요
As for whether you want to execute Chen Jiaping in the future?
앞으로 Chen Jiaping을 처형하고 싶으신가요?
That's your own business
그건 당신 자신의 일이에요
If Chen Jiaping is not the Five of Hearts
Chen Jiaping이 Five of Hearts가 아니라면
Who is the real Five of Hearts?
진짜 파이브 오브 하트는 누구일까요?
and you
당신은요
You can only let your men
당신은 당신의 남자들에게만 허락할 수 있습니다
Put a gun to my head again and ask
또 내 머리에 총을 겨누고 물어봐
Maybe I'll tell you
어쩌면 내가 말해줄게
I know
알아요
Mr. Jiang is probably just pretending to be afraid of death.
장 씨는 아마도 죽음을 두려워하는 척하고 있는 것일 것이다.
The information you told us
알려주신 정보는
seems important
중요한 것 같다
In fact, you have already made up your mind
사실 넌 이미 마음을 정했어
We can't find the recipe or the copper plate at all
레시피나 동판을 전혀 찾을 수 없습니다.
So it doesn't hurt to tell us, right?
그러니 우리에게 말해도 나쁠 것 없겠죠?
Who is the Five of Hearts?
파이브 오브 하트는 누구인가?
Such important information
이런 중요한 정보
you won't tell us
당신은 우리에게 말하지 않을 것입니다
But don't worry
하지만 걱정하지 마세요
I'll find out
내가 알아낼게
Mr. Jiang
장 씨
We did not reach a consensus in this cooperation
우리는 이번 협력에서 합의에 도달하지 못했습니다.
Very sorry
매우 죄송합니다
But if there are regrets, there are expectations
하지만 후회가 있으면 기대도 있다
We have a long way to go
우리 갈 길이 멀다
I'm also looking forward to it
나도 기대된다
Meeting Mr. Uchida again
우치다 씨를 다시 만나다
But I will never give it to you again
하지만 다시는 너한테 주지 않을 거야
A chance to put a gun to my head
내 머리에 총을 겨누는 기회
I don't think so
나는 그렇게 생각하지 않는다
Where is Zhao An?
자오안은 어디에 있나요?
I have no idea
나는 전혀 모른다
I ask you where is Zhao An?
자오안은 어디 있느냐고 묻습니다.
Chief Uchida, I really don’t know.
우치다 국장님, 정말 모르겠어요.
Captain Zhao was always in Tom's car.
자오 선장은 항상 톰의 차에 있었습니다.
I really don't know, Chief Uchida
정말 모르겠어요, 우치다 과장님
After Captain Zhao finished urinating, he asked me to leave first.
자오 선장은 소변을 본 후 나에게 먼저 나가라고 했습니다.
Then he wanted to discuss something with Chen Shugan
그런 다음 그는 Chen Shugan과 무언가 논의하고 싶었습니다.
No
아니요
Captain Zhao didn't get into my car
자오 선장은 내 차에 타지 않았다
He told us to leave quickly
그 사람이 우리한테 빨리 나가라고 했어
He got into the car behind
그 사람이 뒤에서 차를 탔어요
I really do not know
나는 정말로 모른다
Chief Uchida
우치다 소장
we catch someone
우리는 누군가를 붙잡는다
Let him explain the situation
그 사람이 상황을 설명하게 해주세요
look
바라보다
bring people here
사람들을 여기로 데려와
Hou Si
허우시
Say it again what you just told me
방금 나한테 했던 말 다시 한 번 말해봐
Who is the buyer of this batch of cotton yarn?
이 면사 배치의 구매자는 누구입니까?
Boss Zhou
저우 보스
Which Zhou boss
어느 Zhou 상사
It's Du Yuesheng in Chongqing
충칭의 Du Yuesheng입니다
That Tongti company
그 통티회사
Boss Zhou Qingsen specializes in Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Shanghai areas
Boss Zhou Qingsen은 장쑤성, 절강성 및 상하이 지역을 전문으로 합니다.
It is said
라고 한다
He allocated a lot of money
그는 많은 돈을 할당했다
Can get scarce supplies
부족한 재료를 얻을 수 있다
So the buyer is the Chongqing government
그래서 구매자는 충칭 정부입니다.
I'm just an errand boy
난 그냥 심부름꾼이에요
How did you know about this batch of cotton yarn?
이 면사 배치에 대해 어떻게 알았나요?
Boss Zhou told me
주 사장이 나에게 말했다.
He said over there in Shanghai
그는 상하이에서 말했다.
Is there someone who can get the best cotton yarn?
가장 좋은 면사를 구할 수 있는 사람이 있나요?
who's that person
저 사람은 누구야?
He didn't say it directly
그 사람이 직접적으로 말한 건 아니고
But once
하지만 한번
I heard him call that guy
그 사람이 그 사람한테 전화하는 걸 들었어
I heard that he seemed to be from the military command
군부대 출신인 것 같다고 들었는데
What's the code name?
코드명이 무엇인가요?
five of hearts
다섯 개의 하트
Chief Uchida
우치다 소장
This is called Chen Shugan
첸슈간(Chen Shugan)이라고 합니다.
He is Zhao An’s confidant
그는 Zhao An???의 절친한 친구입니다
Since he is a confidant
그 사람은 절친한 사람이니까
You don't know
당신은 모른다
Your Captain Zhao is the Five of Hearts of the military commander, right?
당신의 자오 선장은 군 사령관의 파이브 오브 하트죠?
impossible
불가능한
This is absolutely impossible
이건 절대 불가능해요
Chief Uchida
우치다 소장
There's no way he doesn't know
그 사람이 모를 리가 없잖아
I really don't know anything
난 정말 아무것도 몰라
Chief Uchida, I really don’t know.
우치다 국장님, 정말 모르겠어요.
you believe me
당신은 나를 믿으세요
What do you say
당신은 무엇을 말합니까?
Why doesn’t Boss Zhou come?
주 보스는 왜 안 오나요?
I do not know either
나도 모른다
We agreed to meet here at five o'clock
우리는 여기서 5시에 만나기로 약속했어요
Could it be that he discovered in advance that there was an ambush here?
혹시 이곳에 매복이 있다는 사실을 미리 알아차린 것은 아닐까?
Run away first
먼저 도망가세요
I see
알겠어요
I understand, Chief Uchida.
알겠습니다, 우치다 대장.
Zhao An deceived us all
조안은 우리 모두를 속였습니다
He deliberately let us continue here
그는 의도적으로 우리가 여기서 계속하도록 허락했습니다
Just to distract you
단지 당신의 주의를 분산시키려고
He had time to escape
그에겐 탈출할 시간이 있었다
Chief Uchida, this matter has nothing to do with me.
우치다 국장님, 이번 일은 나와는 상관이 없습니다.
I really do not know
나는 정말로 모른다
What you said seems to make sense
당신이 말한 것이 의미가 있는 것 같습니다
Chief Uchida
우치다 소장
Please spare my life
내 생명을 살려주세요
spare my life
내 목숨을 살려줘
I will be a cow and a horse for you from now on
나는 이제부터 당신을 위해 소와 말이 될 것입니다
As long as you don't kill me
당신이 나를 죽이지 않는 한
Then why don't I think
그럼 내 생각에는 왜 안될까?
You and Zhao An are accomplices
당신과 자오안은 공범이다
You lead us away
당신은 우리를 멀리 이끌어
So that he can cover his escape.
그가 탈출을 은폐할 수 있도록 말이죠.
No
아니요
I don't
나는 아니에요
Shuyun
슈윤
Why did you come?
왜 왔나요?
problem occurs
문제가 발생하다
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
you
너
Why are you carrying such a big box?
왜 이렇게 큰 상자를 들고 다니세요?
Here are all my belongings
여기 내 소지품이 모두 있어요
What's the meaning
무슨 뜻인가요?
The days when I followed the Japanese
일본인을 따르던 시절
Completely over
완전히 끝났어
Thanks to my bright brain
내 밝은 두뇌 덕분에
Escaped
탈출
Otherwise you won't be able to see me
그렇지 않으면 당신은 나를 볼 수 없습니다
Chen Shugan them
첸 슈간 그들
died
사망 한
So what should we do now?
그럼 이제 우리는 무엇을 해야 할까요?
I'll go to Pudong with you
나는 당신과 함께 푸동에 갈 것이다
Let's hide for a while
잠시 숨어보자
Then find a way to leave Shanghai
그렇다면 상하이를 떠날 방법을 찾아보세요
What about after that?
그 후에는 어떻습니까?
Will we keep escaping like this from now on?
앞으로도 계속 이대로 도망칠 것인가?
You are my only support now
당신은 이제 나의 유일한 지지자입니다
You can't let me live like this
날 이렇게 살게 놔둘 순 없어
Shuyun
슈윤
Believe me
나를 믿어
There's enough money in the box to last us a lifetime
상자 안에는 우리가 평생 지낼 수 있을 만큼 충분한 돈이 있어요
I'll take you to Hong Kong
내가 널 홍콩으로 데려갈게
let's buy a big house
큰 집을 사자
I'll go there to invest and do some business.
나는 그곳에 가서 투자하고 사업을 할 것입니다.
Our life won't be bad
우리 인생도 나쁘지 않을 거야
By the time
그때쯤에는
I will organize a grand wedding for you
내가 당신을 위해 성대한 결혼식을 준비해 줄게요
Then you give me a big fat boy
그럼 넌 나한테 크고 뚱뚱한 남자를 줘
We are a family of three
우리는 3인 가족이에요
No need to worry about food or clothing
음식이나 옷에 대해 걱정할 필요가 없습니다
live a good life
좋은 삶을 살아라
go to Hong Kong
홍콩으로 가다
Hongkong
홍콩
Went to his
그에게 갔다
Imperial Army National Army Japanese
제국군 국군 일본군
Get out
나가세요
I have been the grandson of the Japanese for so many years
나는 오랫동안 일본인의 손자였습니다.
Why do I
내가 왜?
I just want to make a lot of money
나는 단지 돈을 많이 벌고 싶을 뿐이다.
I live my life
나는 내 삶을 산다
I let you live a good life with me
나랑 같이 잘 살게 해줄게
Right
오른쪽
Shuyun
슈윤
You have been suffering with me during this time
그동안 나랑 고생했어
I'll replenish it for you later
나중에 보충해줄게
Let's go to the ferry right now
지금 당장 페리로 가자
Wait a moment
잠깐만요
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
I still have something to get
아직 얻을 게 남았어
what is this
이게 뭔가요
Some of my gold and silver are so soft
내 금과 은 중 일부는 너무 부드러워요
There are also some cheongsams I just made.
방금 만든 치파오도 있어요.
where is it
어디야?
I'm hiding in the ruined temple opposite
나는 반대편 폐허가 된 사원에 숨어 있어요
Shuyun
슈윤
Come in Shuyun
들어와 슈윤
come in and save me
들어와서 나를 구해주세요
Shuyun
슈윤
Zhao An
자오안
What are you doing with my wife?
내 아내랑 뭐하는 거야?
I'm here
나는 여기 있다
Luo Guanqun
루오관쿤
why are you here
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
my wife is here
내 아내가 여기 있어요
why can't i be here
나는 왜 여기 있을 수 없나요?
Where's Shuyun?
슈윤은 어디 있지?
she's next to me
그녀는 내 옆에 있어요
Shuyun
슈윤
Say something to Captain Zhao
자오 선장에게 뭐라고 말해보세요
Don't be afraid
두려워하지 마세요
Let the past go by
과거는 지나가게 놔두세요
You behaved very well today
오늘 아주 잘 행동했어
Luo Guanqun, your uncle
Luo Guanqun, 네 삼촌
You coerced Zhang Shuyun
당신은 장수윤(Zhang Shuyun)을 강요했습니다.
Shuyun
슈윤
Zhao An
자오안
Stop talking nonsense here
여기서 말도 안되는 소리는 그만하세요
You forced me from beginning to end
넌 처음부터 끝까지 나를 강요했어
Shuyun
슈윤
I'm sincere to you
나는 당신에게 진심입니다
Have you forgotten how Luo Guanqun beat you?
Luo Guanqun이 당신을 어떻게 이겼는지 잊으셨습니까?
Zhao An
자오안
You don't believe anyone
당신은 누구도 믿지 않아요
I just believe in women
난 그냥 여자를 믿어
But it’s because of women
근데 그건 여자 때문이야
lied to you
당신에게 거짓말을 했어요
you have to die
너는 죽어야 해
he was angry
그는 화가 났었 다
buried him
그를 묻었다
Shuyun
슈윤
Don't listen
듣지 마세요
Don't listen to Luo Guanqun lie to you
Luo Guanqun이 거짓말하는 것을 듣지 마십시오
You just buried me
넌 나를 그냥 묻어버렸어
He won't let you go either
그 사람도 널 놓아주지 않을 거야
Did you hear Shuyun?
슈윤 들었어?
Shuyun
슈윤
Luo Guanqun, stop it
뤄관쿤, 그만해
I didn't bury you
난 당신을 묻지 않았어요
It was Shuyun who buried you
너를 묻어준 건 슈윤이었어
Shuyun
슈윤
He is lying to you Shuyun
그는 당신에게 거짓말을 하고 있어요 슈윤
come on
어서 해봐요
Luo Guanqun
루오관쿤
Please let me go
가게 해 줘
I have money
나는 돈이 있다
I'll give you all the money
돈은 다 줄게
Look, that box is full of money.
보세요, 그 상자에는 돈이 가득 들어 있어요.
this is the key
이것이 핵심이다
Give
주다
I throw it up
나는 그것을 던진다
Look at the money in the box
상자에 돈 좀 봐
for you
당신을 위한
Zhao An
자오안
I'd like to see
나는보고 싶다
How much money have you made in the past few years?
지난 몇 년 동안 돈을 얼마나 벌었나요?
Zhao An
자오안
You really didn't disappoint me
당신은 정말 나를 실망시키지 않았어요
Luo Guanqun will give it to you
Luo Guanqun이 당신에게 줄 것입니다
Shuyun
슈윤
I beg you
부탁드립니다
Stop pouring dirt, Shuyun
흙 좀 그만 쏟아부어 슈윤아
You have to save me Shuyun
날 구해줘야 해 슈윤
Shuyun, look inside the box
슈윤아, 상자 안을 봐
I have a gift for you Shuyun
슈윤이한테 선물을 줬어
Last time we saw it together
저번에 같이 봤었는데
I want to surprise you
나는 당신을 놀라게하고 싶습니다
Take a look at Shuyun
슈윤을 보세요
This is the gift Captain Zhao bought for you
이건 자오 선장이 당신에게 사준 선물이에요
How do you want to deal with it
어떻게 처리하고 싶나요?
Qun Ge
쿤 게
I was wrong, Brother Qun
내가 틀렸어요, 쿤 형제님
Spare my life, Brother Qun
살려주세요, 쿤 형제님
I, Zhao An, am finished
나, 조안(Zhao An)은 끝났다
I can't stay in Shanghai any longer
나는 더 이상 상하이에 머물 수 없다
I go
나 간다
Qun Ge
쿤 게
Spare my life, Brother Qun
살려주세요, 쿤 형제님
I was wrong
내가 틀렸어
I shouldn't seek your position
난 네 자리를 구하면 안 돼
I shouldn't steal your goods
네 물건을 훔치면 안 돼
I shouldn't have any bad thoughts about Mrs. Luo
루오 부인에 대해 나쁜 생각을 가져서는 안 됩니다.
I beg you
부탁드립니다
Spare my life
내 목숨을 살려주세요
I beg you, Brother Qun
부탁드립니다, 쿤 형제님
Zhao An
자오안
You also have today
너도 오늘은
Shuyun
슈윤
I am sincere to you Shuyun
나는 당신에게 진심입니다 슈윤
I really want to take you away
정말 널 데려가고 싶어
Break his spell and break the net
그의 주문을 깨고 그물을 부수세요
Lift the barrier of death and disaster
죽음과 재난의 장벽을 허물다
Save all injustice and suffering
모든 불의와 고통을 구하소서
Clean, bright and more auspicious
깨끗하고 밝고 더 상서로운
Break his spell and break the net
그의 주문을 깨고 그물을 부수세요
Lift the barrier of death and disaster
죽음과 재난의 장벽을 허물다
rescue
구조하다
Zhao An
자오안
Huangquan Road
황취안 로드
I'll give you a ride
내가 태워줄게
I am sincerely Shuyun
진심으로 슈윤이에요
I want to live a good life with you
나는 당신과 함께 좋은 삶을 살고 싶습니다
I want to take you away
너를 데려가고 싶어
buy a big house
큰 집을 사다
give birth
출산하다
I want to give you a good life
나는 당신에게 좋은 삶을주고 싶습니다
All squatted
모두 쪼그리고 앉았다
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
Zhao An's men
조안의 부하들
Except for those who were arrested last night
어젯밤에 체포된 사람들을 제외하고
All the rest is here
나머지는 다 여기 있어요
Zhao An colluded with the military
자오안은 군부와 공모했다
Do you know the evidence?
증거를 아시나요?
It’s not a matter of one or two days.
하루 이틀의 문제가 아닙니다.
You must know a thing or two
당신은 한두 가지를 알아야합니다
If there is a problem, there is evidence
문제가 있으면 증거가 있다
Report everything to me
나한테 다 신고해
If you cover up and conceal
은폐하고 숨기면
The consequences will be the same as him
결과는 그 사람과 같을 겁니다
large spoon
큰 숟가락
exist
존재하다
if they don't say
그들이 말하지 않으면
Get my teeth punched
이빨에 구멍이 뚫리네
If you don't say it again
다시 말하지 않으면
Take out your heart for me
나를 위해 마음을 꺼내주세요
yes
예
How about it
어때요?
Do you understand?
이해했나요?
Who wants to report and expose Zhao An?
자오안(Zhao An)을 신고하고 폭로하고 싶은 사람이 누구입니까?
Now give you a chance
이제 너에게 기회를 줘
I know
알아요
I said
나는 말했다
I know too
나도 알아
I also said
나도 말했다
Don't worry
괜찮아요
Come one by one
한명씩 오세요
You speak first
당신이 먼저 말을 걸어요
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
Where do you think Captain Zhao fled to?
자오 선장이 어디로 도망쳤다고 생각하시나요?
how could I know
내가 어떻게 알아
I estimate that he is probably dead.
나는 그가 아마도 죽었을 것으로 추정합니다.
what do you think
어떻게 생각하나요
I also accidentally heard it a few days ago
저도 며칠전에 우연히 들었는데
Captain Zhao is in his office
자오 선장이 사무실에 있어요
Planning an escape
탈출을 계획하다
Manager Luo, don’t worry
루오 매니저님, 걱정하지 마세요
I understand
이해합니다
See many things with your eyes
눈으로 많은 것을 보아라
Put it in the stomach
뱃속에 넣어두세요
But it must not leak out of your mouth
단, 입 밖으로 새어나오면 안 된다.
Qian Xiucai
치안 슈카이
I know you helped me with this matter
나는 당신이 이 문제에 대해 나를 도왔다는 것을 알고 있습니다
I remember it
나 그거 기억 해요
By the way, Manager Luo
그런데 루오 매니저님
Have you read the Chronicles of the Eastern Zhou Dynasties?
동주왕조실록을 읽어보셨나요?
What about Wei State?
웨이 주는 어떻습니까?
There was a janitor named Hou Ying
허우잉(Hou Ying)이라는 관리인이 있었습니다.
Have a strategy in mind
전략을 염두에 두세요
But hide it
하지만 숨기세요
Until I met Mr. Xinling
신링 선생님을 만나기 전까지
Only by oneself can one see the virtuous
오직 자기만이 덕을 볼 수 있다
And finally became Lord Xinling
그리고 마침내 Xinling 경이 되었습니다.
Offered a plan to steal the talisman to save Zhao
자오를 구하기 위해 부적을 훔치려는 계획을 제안했습니다.
Protected Wei State
보호된 웨이 상태
what do you mean
무슨 뜻이에요
without
없이
nothing
아무것도 아님
That is, if Manager Luo is interested, he would like to read it.
즉, 루 감독이 관심이 있다면 읽어보고 싶다는 것이다.
Words from the Chronicles of the States of the Eastern Zhou Dynasty
동주(周周)나라실록에 나오는 말씀
I can lend it to you anytime
언제든지 빌려줄 수 있어요
Qian Xiucai
치안 슈카이
you
너
what is your real name
당신의 진짜 이름은 무엇입니까
Qian Chengyi
첸 청이
sun gongyi pawn
손공이 폰
The one who becomes one in the end
결국 하나가 되는 사람
Manager Luo
루오 매니저
I really didn't expect that
정말 그럴 줄은 예상 못했어요
Zhao An is the real Five of Hearts
자오안은 진짜 5심이다
yes
예
I didn’t expect that the five hearts were hidden so deeply.
다섯 개의 하트가 이렇게 깊게 숨겨져 있을 줄은 몰랐습니다.
Zhao An fled in fear of crime
자오안(Zhao An)은 범죄를 두려워하여 도망쳤다
This further proves our Jiaping’s innocence.
이는 우리 Jiaping의 결백을 더욱 입증합니다.
Jiang Zhaoguo suddenly overturned his confession
장자오궈(江趙國)가 갑자기 자백을 번복했다.
Saying that the Five of Hearts is not Chen Jiaping
5심은 천가평이 아니라고 한다
Do you think this is strange?
이것이 이상하다고 생각하시나요?
What's so strange about this?
이게 뭐가 그렇게 이상해요?
Doesn't he always hold grudges?
그 사람은 항상 원한을 품고 있지 않나요?
Are Jia Ping and Han Lu close?
Jia Ping과 Han Lu는 가까운가요?
Only intentionally framed
의도적으로 액자에 넣었을 뿐
Since everyone has come to the rescue
모두가 구조하러 왔기 때문에
He had no choice but to tell the truth
그는 진실을 말할 수밖에 없었습니다
Am I right
내가 맞나요?
five of hearts
다섯 개의 하트
Four of clubs
클럽 4개
You said we should go find Chief Uchida this time
이번에는 우치다 대장을 찾으러 가자고 했잖아
Can you bring Jia Ping out smoothly?
Jia Ping을 원활하게 데려올 수 있나요?
The evidence is complete
증거가 완전하다
but
하지만
It’s hard to say Japanese people
일본사람이라고 하기엔 어렵네요
Chen Jiaping
첸 지아핑
It's hard to say
말하기 어렵다
It's been several days
며칠이 지났어요
There is no news about Jia Ping
지아핑에 대한 소식은 없습니다
Imprisoned in that terrible place
그 끔찍한 곳에 갇혔어
I really don't know what will happen
무슨 일이 일어날지 정말 모르겠어요
What book are you reading?
어떤 책을 읽고 있나요?
The Japanese can't even understand a loyal traitor like you
일본놈들은 너같은 충성스러운 반역자를 이해하지도 못해
All caught
다 잡혔어
So blind
너무 눈이 멀어
at the beginning
처음에
I thought about climbing over the wall and getting out.
담을 넘어 밖으로 나갈까도 생각했다.
But later I discovered
그런데 나중에 알게 됐어요.
Totally impossible
전혀 불가능
Can you see the entire building clearly?
건물 전체가 선명하게 보이나요?
The first floor is where Japanese activities take place.
1층은 일본 활동이 이루어지는 곳입니다.
There is a canteen on the far right
맨 오른쪽에 식당이 있어요
There's a back door leading outside
바깥으로 통하는 뒷문이 있어요
And we have to go down to the first floor through the second floor
그리고 2층을 거쳐 1층으로 내려가야 해요
You have to go through three iron gates first
먼저 세 개의 철문을 통과해야 합니다
There are four more iron gates to pass behind.
뒤로 지나갈 철문이 4개 더 있습니다.
to escape
탈출
That's the escape route
그게 탈출 경로야
Remember clearly
똑똑히 기억해
The show starts at eight o'clock
공연은 8시에 시작해요
A total of eight programs
총 8개 프로그램
If you want to escape
탈출하고 싶다면
Must escape before the show ends
쇼가 끝나기 전에 탈출해야 합니다